In order to break the code, one man will have to break all the rules.
National Treasure is a adventure, action, thriller
film directed by Jon Turteltaub.
Modern treasure hunters, led by archaeologist Ben Gates, search for a chest of riches rumored to have been stashed
away by George Washington, Thomas Jefferson and Benjamin Franklin during the Revolutionary War.
The chest's whereabouts may lie in secret clues embedded in the Constitution and the Declaration
of Independence, and Gates is in a race to find the gold before his enemies do.
Benjamin Franklin Gates, played by Nicolas Cage.
Abigail Chase, played by Diane Kruger.
Riley Poole, played by Justin Bartha.
Ian Howe, played by Sean Bean.
Patrick Gates, played by Jon Voight.
Peter Sadusky, played by Harvey Keitel.
National Treasure is a 2004 action-adventure heist
film released by Walt Disney Pictures.
It was directed by Jon Turteltaub, written by Jim Kouf and the
Wibberleys, and produced by Jerry Bruckheimer.
It is the first film in the National Treasure franchise and stars Nicolas Cage in the lead role,
Harvey Keitel, Jon Voight, Diane Kruger, Sean Bean, Justin Bartha and Christopher Plummer.
In the film, Benjamin Franklin Gates, a historian, along with computer expert Riley Poole and archivist Abigail Chase, search for a
massive lost Freemason treasure, which includes a map hidden on the back of the United States Declaration of Independence.
National Treasure was released worldwide on November 19, 2004.
The film grossed $347 million worldwide and received mixed reviews from critics.
A sequel, National Treasure: Book of Secrets, was released in 2007.
A sequel television series, National Treasure: Edge of History,
premiered on the Disney+ streaming service in 2022.
The film explores themes of new york city, treasure,
philadelphia, pennsylvania, washington dc, usa, riddle.
The tone is mind_bending and intense.